Guide to the George B. Darling Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1920s-1979; Series IV
  Additional files in the series relate to Darling's work during the 1940s and early 1950s. The First Eleven Years (folder 11) is a report to the Kellogg Foundation trustees by Darling as president and Emory Morris as general director. It summarizes the foundation's early efforts in the field ofcommunity health and health education. The medical research sponsored by the National Research Council during World War II is detailed by Darling in his chapter in Doctors at War (folder 13). Writings dating from Darling's years as the director of the division of medical affairs of Yale University concern the costs of medical education and research and were written to garner financial and political support for increased funding.
  - "After the Tremendous", Circa 1920s (Box 38, Folder 1-2)
  - "Rabies-A Statistical Review", 1929 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - "Visual Rate Chart", 1932 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - "School Health Programs", Circa 1932-1939 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - "A Community Participation Health Program", 1933 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - "The Michigan Community Health Project ofthe W. K. Kellogg Foundation", 1935 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - "W. K. Kellogg Foundation", 1938 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - "M.C.H.P.", 1938 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Notes for various talks, 1940s-1952, undated (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - The First Eleven Years, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - "Opportunities for Inter-American Exchange Services in the Training of Public Health Personnel", 1943, 1945 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Doctors at War, 1945 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Testimony before the Interstate and Foreign Commerce Committee of the United States House of Representatives hearings on medical research, 1948 May 14 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - "The Place of Yale Medical School in Connecticut Medicine", 1949 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - "Can We Pay for Our Medical School", 1950 See also: Series I, folder 6 (Box 39, Folder 16-17)
  - Religious Sanctions in Public Health [notes for a special study with the Divinity School and the National Council of Churches of Christ], 1953 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Brief statements as director of the Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1957-1965 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Letter to the Japan Times, 1958 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - "ABCC Section in Hiroshima Igaku", 1960 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Lecture to the students of Hiroshima Nursing School, 1963 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Brief statements as director of the Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1966-1969 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Remarks at a meeting with Drs. Belsky, Pastore, and Robertson, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Brief statements as director of the Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission, 1970-1972 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Talk to the ABCC professional staff in Hiroshima, 1970 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - "On the 25th A-Bomb Anniversary", 1970 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - "Human Ecology and Medical Care", 1970 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - "Preface to Research Protocols 1969 Jul 1 - 1970 Jun 30", 1971 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Comment on the fiscal problem at the ABCC staff meeting, 1971 (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - "Introduction", 1972 (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - "Atomic Bomb Casualty Commission" [Association of Military Surgeons of the United States], 1973 (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Report for Detlev Bronk on ABCC, Circa 1973-1974
    - Introduction (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - Pattern of binational reports (Box 39, Folder 34)
    - ABCC and Medical Care
      - Pp. 1-53 (Box 39, Folder 35)
      - Pp.54-148 (Box 40, Folder 36-37)
    - ABCC and GLJ [pp. 149-224] (Box 40, Folder 38)
    - ABCC and Japanese Supporting Staff [pp. 225-290] (Box 40, Folder 39)
    - Motor transport [pp.291-305] (Box 40, Folder 40)
    - Housing [pp. 306-350] (Box 40, Folder 41)
    - Schools [pp. 351-359] (Box 40, Folder 42)
  - John E. Fogarty International Center for Advanced Study in the Health Sciences [seminar presentation notes], 1974 (Box 40, Folder 43)
  - "Henry Frieze Vaughan", 1979 (Box 40, Folder 44)
  - Testimony before a meeting [National Academy of Sciences?], undated (Box 40, Folder 45)
- Personal and Family Papers, 1805-1995; Series V
  This series includes personal papers of George and Ann Darling, as well as correspondence, legal and financial records, and memorabilia of their various Darling, Reed, Shaw, and Whittemore antecedents. Family materials from the nineteenth century encompass memorabilia from Boston, and Concord, Vermont, as well as Civil War era clippings and newspapers from South Carolina, which were collected by Margaret Whittemore in her scrapbook. Personal papers of George Darling's parents, Alice Smith and George B. Darling, Sr., document their lives in Boston, George's military preparedness training in Plattsburg, New York and career with C. F. Hovey and Shepard Stores and Alice's volunteer activities.
  Ann Shaw Darling was a conscientious chronicler and her files include both personal and travel diaries, as well as notes on reading and entertaining. Her personal diaries, which span the years 1937 through 1983, contain brief entries recording her life in Michigan, Washington, and New Haven. The entries become more detailed during her first few years in Japan as she describes life in Hiroshima, entertaining for guests, and trips around the countryside. The travel diaries portray the style in which the Darlings traveled as well as the extent of their voyages. The files also include a draft of Ann Darling's memoirs of her years in Japan and a copy of the book she co-authored, How to Be Reasonably Well-Mannered at a Japanese Tea Ceremony.
  Personal papers of George Darling begin with appointment books that span almost his entire professional career. Only books from his early years at the W. K. Kellogg Foundation are not included. To some of these volumes Darling added photographs and other bits of memorabilia. Since George Darling did not keep a diary, except during the summer of 1922, these appointment books are useful in following Darling's activities. The series includes memorabilia from Darling's student days and early travels. There are also several folders of souvenirs saved from his participation in Operation Crossroads and memorabilia of special significance from his years in the Far East.
  - Darling, Alice Smith
    - Correspondence, 1913, 1936 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Legal and financial papers [includes copies of birth and marriage certificates], 1904-1929 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Memorabilia
      - Education, marriage, courtship, 1902-1927 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Daughters of the Revolution, Circa 1904-1919 (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - Pilgrim Woman's Club, Boston City Federation, etc.], 1920-1923 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Funeral, 1957 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Darling, Ann
    - Autograph book, 1923-1924 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Diaries
    - Personal
      - 1937-1960 (Box 41, Folder 8-10)
      - 1961-1983 (Box 42, Folder 11-12)
      - Travel
        - 1933-1956 (Box 42, Folder 13-14)
        - 1961 Apr-1964 Feb (Box 42, Folder 15)
        - 1964 Oct-1983 May (Box 43, Folder 16-19)
    - Genealogical papers, Circa 1976-1977 (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Guest books, 1938-1961 (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Legal and financial papers
      - General, 1951-1962 (Box 44, Folder 22)
      - Texas land, 1952-1966 (Box 44, Folder 23)
    - Memorabilia
      - Baby book, 1901 (Box 44, Folder 24)
      - High school, 1919 (Box 44, Folder 25)
      - Trip to Europe, 1929 (Box 44, Folder 26)
      - Wedding, 1931 (Box 44, Folder 27)
      - Travel, 1953 (Box 44, Folder 28)
    - Notebooks
      - Books, theatre, 1927-1953 (Box 44, Folder 29)
      - Christmas (Box 44, Folder 30)
      - Visitors and entertaining, 1957-1982 (Box 44, Folder 31)
    - Notes on Japan [includes draft of memoirs], Circa 1957-1972 (Box 45, Folder 32)
    - Notes on travel, 1939 (Box 45, Folder 33)
    - Writings [ How to Be Reasonably Well-Mannered at a Japanese Tea Ceremony ], 1972 (Box 45, Folder 34)
  - Darling, George B., Sr.
    - Correspondence, 1894-1928, undated (Box 45, Folder 35)
    - Bookrecords, 1901-1928 (Box 45, Folder 36-40)
    - Clippings, 1920s (Box 45, Folder 41)
    - Memorabilia
      - C. F. Hovey Co., 1914-1920 (Box 46, Folder 42)
      - Military training, Plattsburgh, N.Y., 1916 (Box 46, Folder 43)
      - Shepard Stores, funeral, 1921-1928 (Box 46, Folder 44)
    - Writings, 1913-1919, undated (Box 46, Folder 45)
  - Darling, George B., Jr.
    - Appointment books
      - 1943-1952 (Box 46, Folder 46-50)
      - 1953-1974 (Box 47, Folder 51-59)
      - 1975-1977,1981-1982 (Box 48, Folder 60-61)
    - Articles and clippings about, 1938, 1965-1975 (Box 48, Folder 62)
    - Diary, 1922 (Box 48, Folder 63)
    - Memorabilia
      - 1905 (Box 48, Folder 64)
      - High scbool, 1918-1923 (Box 48, Folder 65)
      - Summer camp work, ROTC, 1923-1926 (Box 48, Folder 66)
      - M.I.T. including Engineering News, 1925-1926 (Box 48, Folder 67)
      - M.I.T. including Engineering News, 1926-1927 (Box 49, Folder 68-69)
      - School health and health education tour of Europe, 1929 (Box 49, Folder 70)
      - 1930-1956 (Box 49, Folder 71)
      - West Indies trip, 1935 (Box 49, Folder 72)
      - Europe and Mediterranean trip, 1936 (Box 50, Folder 73)
      - South American trip, 1941 (Box 50, Folder 74)
      - Operation Crossroads, 1946 (Box 50, Folder 75-81)
      - Japan, 1957-1972
        - General (Box 50, Folder 82)
        - Japan Medical Association Supreme Award, [1967] (Box 51, Folder 83)
        - Retirement, [1972] (Box 51, Folder 84)
        - Rotary Club of Japan (Box 51, Folder 85)
        - Shikishi (Box 51, Folder 86)
        - U.S. Atomic Energy Commission citation, [1970] (Box 51, Folder 87)
      - 1973-1995 (Box 51, Folder 88)
      - n.d. (Box 51, Folder 89)
    - Notes, 1953-1954 (Box 51, Folder 90-91)
    - Personal data, Circa 1937-1972 (Box 51, Folder 92-93)
    - Reading notes, Circa 1930s-1950, undated (Box 51, Folder 94-96)
    - Scrapbooks, 1938-1951 (Box 52, Folder 97)
      See also: Oversize, folder 2
  - Darling family, 1841-1897, undated (Box 52, Folder 98)
    See also: Oversize, folder 3
  - Reed, Smith, and Gardner family, 1805-1888, undated (Box 52, Folder 99)
  - Shaw, Ed, 1887, 1940 (Box 52, Folder 100)
  - Whittemore, Clare
    - Letters, 1929, 1936-1938, undated (Box 52, Folder 101)
    - Log of trip to the West Coast, 1938 (Box 52, Folder 102-104)
    - Memoirs, Circa 1930s
      - From 1890 to 1895 (Box 52, Folder 105)
      - 1893 (Box 52, Folder 106)
      - Association with E. C. Shaw, 1893-1936 (Box 52, Folder 107)
      - Trip to Hawaii, 1895 (Box 52, Folder 108)
      - Trip to California (Box 52, Folder 109)
      - Trip to Japan, China, and the Philippines, 1903 (Box 52, Folder 110)
      - 1931-1932, undated (Box 52, Folder 111)
  - Whittemore, Margaret [scrapbook], Circa 1861-1880s (Box 52, Folder 112-113)
    See also: Oversize, folder 4
- Photographs, 1813-1995; Series VI
  This series contains the Darling's extensive collection of photographs, which includes portraits of family members, images taken on their many trips around the world, and an extensive visual record of their years spent in Japan. The series does not include the occasional photograph of children or family events sent by friends as enclosures in their letters. These photographs remain with their letters of transmittal, primarily in Series I.
  The series is arranged by photographic type, beginning with the daguerreotypes and images captured by other early photographic processes. There are also some silhouettes. These early photographs are mainly of Darling, Smith, and Whittemore family members.
  A large assemblage of photographic prints includes additional images of family members, colleagues and mends, and portraits and candid shots of Ann and George Darling. Each of these sections is arranged in alphabetical order by name. The remainder of the prints are arranged in chronological order beginning with photographs from George Darling's student days and Operation Crossroads. The vast majority of the prints, however, date from the Darlings' years in Japan. The prints include both formal publicity photographs and more candid shots from official visits of dignitaries to the ABCC, advisory board meetings, social functions, and ceremonial occasions. The prints also include photographs of ABCC staff and their families and of the Darlings' vacation trips.
  Slides the Darlings collected are arranged at the end of the series. The earliest slides, those from Yale and Connecticut of the 1950s, were obviously taken by amateur photographers, probably the Darlings themselves. The other slides are primarily those from various trips to the Far East, Latin America, Africa, and Europe. There are occasional slides that the Darlings purchased, but, for the most part, these slides represent the Darling's own views of their travels.
  - Daguerreotypes and other early photographic images
    - Darling, George Bancroft, undated (Box 53, Folder 1-2)
    - Darling, Margaret Whittemore, undated (Box 53, Folder 3-5)
    - Smith, Emeline L., undated (Box 53, Folder 6-7)
    - Smith, Emily Susan Gardner, undated (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Smith, G. W. L., undated (Box 53, Folder 9-10)
    - Smith, Luther, undated (Box 54, Folder 11-13)
    - Whittemore, Aaron, undated (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Whittemore, Reed, undated (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Prints
    - Family
      - Darling, Agnes, undated (Box 55, Folder 17)
      - Darling, George Bancroft, Undated (Box 55, Folder 18)
      - Darling, George Bapst (1879-1921), 1879-1888 (Box 55, Folder 19-20)
      - Darling, John Metcalf, undated (Box 55, Folder 21)
      - Darling, Margaret Whittemore, 1878 (Box 55, Folder 22)
      - Gardner family, Circa 1813 (Box 55, Folder 23)
      - Shaw family, 1893 and undated (Box 55, Folder 24)
      - Smith family, 1881-1900 (Box 55, Folder 25)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 55, Folder 26-27)
    - Friends and acquaintances
      - General, 1950-1985 (Box 55, Folder 28-29)
      - Grace-New Haven Community Hospital, 1945
        See: Series II, folder 51
      - Yale University faculty and classes, 1945-1959 (Box 55, Folder 30)
        See also: Oversize, folder 5
    - Portraits and candids
      - Darling, Ann Shaw
        - 1908-1913 (Box 55, Folder 31)
        - Trip out West, Circa 1923 (Box 56, Folder 32)
        - 1953, undated (Box 56, Folder 33)
        - With George Bapst Darling
          See: folders 36-37
      - Darling, George Bapst (1905-1995)
        - ca. 1910-1975 (Box 56, Folder 34-35)
        - With Ann Shaw Darling, 1935-1987 (Box 56, Folder 36-37)
    - Chronological
      - 1925-1926, ca. 1932 (Box 56, Folder 38)
      - Operation Crossroads, 1946 (Box 56, Folder 39-40)
      - Cut-in-Two Island scenes, 1950s (Box 56, Folder 41)
      - 1957-1972
        - Japan
          - General (Box 56, Folder 42-43)
            See also: Oversiz~ folder 6
          - Fashion show
            See: Oversize, folder 7
          - Flower arrangements (Box 57, Folder 44)
          - Scenery (Box 57, Folder 45)
      - 1957 (Box 57, Folder 46)
      - 1958
        - Japan
          - General (Box 57, Folder 47-49)
          - Hakone and Mt. Fuji trip (Box 57, Folder 50)
          - Matsue trip (Box 57, Folder 51)
      - 1959 (Box 57, Folder 54)
      - 1960 (Box 57, Folder 54)
      - 1961 (Box 57, Folder 55)
      - 1962 (Box 57, Folder 56-57)
      - 1963 (Box 57, Folder 58-60)
      - 1964 (Box 58, Folder 61)
      - 1965 (Box 58, Folder 62-63)
      - 1966
        - Japan: general (Box 58, Folder 64)
        - Travel: Kenya, Nepal, India (Box 58, Folder 65-67)
      - 1967
        - Japan
          - General (Box 58, Folder 68)
          - Japan Medical Association award (Box 59, Folder 69)
      - 1968 (Box 59, Folder 70-71)
        - Japan
          - General
          - ABCC farewell (Box 60, Folder 87)
          - Advisory Committee on ABCC (Box 60, Folder 88)
          - Goodbye party (Box 60, Folder 89)
      - 1969
        - Japan
          - General (Box 59, Folder 72)
          - Annual Advisory Committee Meeting (Box 59, Folder 73-74)
          - Atomic Energy Commission citation (Box 59, Folder 75-76)
      - 1970
        - Japan
          - General (Box 59, Folder 77)
          - Atomic Energy Commission citation--Hiroshima (Box 59, Folder 78)
      - 1971 (Box 59, Folder 79)
      - 1972
      - 1973-1976 (Box 60, Folder 90)
      - 1977-1979 (Box 61, Folder 91)
      - 1980-1995 (Box 61, Folder 92)
      - no date (Box 61, Folder 93)
  - Slides
    - Yale, New Haven, and other places in Connecticut, 1951-1956 (Box 61, Folder 94)
    - Hawaii, 1960s (Box 61, Folder 95)
    - 1961
      - Blue Lagoon, Fiji (Box 61, Folder 96)
      - Mariposa, Tahiti (Box 61, Folder 97)
      - New Zealand, Australia (Box 61, Folder 98)
    - 1962
      - Bora Bora (Box 62, Folder 99)
      - Ceylon (Box 63, Folder 100)
      - India (Box 63, Folder 101-103)
      - India (Box 64, Folder 104)
      - Italy (Box 64, Folder 105)
      - Egypt [through Suez] (Box 64, Folder 106)
      - New Haven/Washington (Box 64, Folder 107)
    - ca. 1962-1964 (Box 64, Folder 108)
    - 1964
      - Allica (Box 64, Folder 109)
      - Capetown (Box 65, Folder 110)
      - Hong Kong (Box 65, Folder 111)
      - Laurenco Marques (Box 65, Folder 112)
      - Malaysia (Box 65, Folder 113)
      - Mauritius (Box 65, Folder 114)
      - Nairobi (Box 65, Folder 115)
      - Rio de Janeiro (Box 65, Folder 116)
      - Taiwan (Box 65, Folder 117)
    - 1965
      - Norway (Box 66, Folder 118-119)
      - Sweden (Box 66, Folder 120)
      - Wales (Box 66, Folder 121)
    - 1966
      - India (Box 66, Folder 122)
      - Korea (Box 66, Folder 123)
      - Korea (Box 67, Folder 124)
    - Great Barrier Reef, 1967 (Box 67, Folder 125)
    - New Caledonia, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 126)
    - 1969
      - India (Box 67, Folder 127)
      - On board ship (Box 67, Folder 128)
    - New Haven, Hawaii, 1970 (Box 67, Folder 129)
    - 1973 (Box 67, Folder 130)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 68, Folder 131-132)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 69, Folder 133)
    - no date (Box 69)
      - Africa (Box 69, Folder 134-135)
      - Africa (Box 70, Folder 136)
      - Angkor Wat (Box 70, Folder 137)
      - Bangkok (Box 70, Folder 138)
      - Copenhagen (Box 70, Folder 139)
      - India (Box 70, Folder 140-141)
      - India (Box 71, Folder 142-143)
      - Indonesia (Box 71, Folder 144)
      - Khajuraho (Box 71, Folder 145)
      - Kathmandu (Box 71, Folder 146)
      - Nepal (Box 72, Folder 147)
      - Pago Pago (Box 72, Folder 148)
      - Pakistan (Box 72, Folder 149)
      - Philippines (Box 72, Folder 150)
      - Rotary (Box 72, Folder 151)
      - Singapore (Box 72, Folder 152)
      - Udaipur (Box 72, Folder 153)
      - Vietnam [Saigon] (Box 72, Folder 154)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 73, Folder 155)
- Oversize
  - Yale files
    - Budget analysis and recommendations, 1952-1954 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Japanese hierarchy (Box 770)
  - Personal and family papers
    - Darling, George B., Jr. [scrapbook], 1946-1954 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Darling family, 1841-1897, undated (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Whittemore, Margaret [scrapbook], Circa 1863-1865 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Photographs
    - Yale University faculty and classes, Circa 1945-1959 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Japan, 1957-1972
      - General (Box 74, Folder 6)
      - Fashion show (Box 74, Folder 7)